<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<ValueSet xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir">
  <id value="r2bo-reporte-biopsia-vs"/>
  <text>
    <status value="generated"/><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="res-header-id"><b>Generated Narrative: ValueSet r2bo-reporte-biopsia-vs</b></p><a name="r2bo-reporte-biopsia-vs"> </a><a name="hcr2bo-reporte-biopsia-vs"> </a><p>This value set includes codes based on the following rules:</p><ul><li>Include codes from<a href="http://loinc.org"><code>http://loinc.org</code></a><span title="Version is not explicitly stated. No matching Code System found"> version Not Stated (use latest from terminology server)</span> where COMPONENT  = LP121003-0 (Pathology biopsy report)</li><li>Include codes from<a href="http://www.snomed.org/"><code>http://snomed.info/sct</code></a><span title="Version is not explicitly stated. No matching Code System found"> version Not Stated (use latest from terminology server)</span> where concept  descends from 371528001 (Pathology report)</li></ul></div>
  </text>
  <url value="https://interoperabilidad.minsal.cl/fhir/ig/r2bo/ValueSet/r2bo-reporte-biopsia-vs"/>
  <version value="0.1.1-ballot"/>
  <name value="ReporteBiopsiaVS"/>
  <title value="Set de Valores de los Reportes de Biopsia"/>
  <status value="draft"/>
  <experimental value="true"/>
  <date value="2025-12-12T16:54:01-03:00"/>
  <publisher value="Unidad de Interoperabilidad - MINSAL"/>
  <contact>
    <name value="Unidad de Interoperabilidad - MINSAL"/>
    <telecom>
      <system value="url"/>
      <value value="https://interoperabilidad.minsal.cl"/>
    </telecom>
  </contact>
  <contact>
    <name value="Franco Ulloa"/>
    <telecom>
      <system value="email"/>
      <value value="franco.ulloa@minsal.cl"/>
      <use value="work"/>
    </telecom>
  </contact>
  <description value="Códigos de tipos de reportes de biopsias en Snomed y LOINC"/>
  <jurisdiction>
    <coding>
      <system value="urn:iso:std:iso:3166"/>
      <code value="CL"/>
      <display value="Chile"/>
    </coding>
  </jurisdiction>
  <copyright value="This value set includes content from SNOMED CT, which is copyright © 2002+ International Health Terminology Standards Development Organisation (IHTSDO), and distributed by agreement between IHTSDO and HL7. Implementer use of SNOMED CT is not covered by this agreement&#xA;&#xA;The SNOMED International IPS Terminology is distributed by International Health Terminology Standards Development Organisation, trading as SNOMED International, and is subject the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Public License. For more information, see SNOMED IPS Terminology&#xA;&#xA;The HL7 International IPS implementation guides incorporate SNOMED CT®, used by permission of the International Health Terminology Standards Development Organisation, trading as SNOMED International. SNOMED CT was originally created by the College of American Pathologists. SNOMED CT is a registered trademark of the International Health Terminology Standards Development Organisation, all rights reserved. Implementers of SNOMED CT should review usage terms or directly contact SNOMED International: info@snomed.org&#xA;&#xA;This material contains content from LOINC (http://loinc.org). LOINC is copyright © 1995-2020, Regenstrief Institute, Inc. and the Logical Observation Identifiers Names and Codes (LOINC) Committee and is available at no cost under the license at http://loinc.org/license. LOINC® is a registered United States trademark of Regenstrief Institute, Inc"/>
  <compose>
    <include>
      <system value="http://loinc.org"/>
      <filter>
        <property value="COMPONENT"/>
        <op value="="/>
        <value value="LP121003-0"/>
      </filter>
    </include>
    <include>
      <system value="http://snomed.info/sct"/>
      <filter>
        <property value="concept"/>
        <op value="descendent-of"/>
        <value value="371528001"/>
      </filter>
    </include>
  </compose>
</ValueSet>